[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
[SCREAMING IN PAIN]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- [ENGINE REVVING]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[ENGINES REVVING]
[TRUCK HORN BLARES]
[LOUD CRASH]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- Stop!
- [GUNSHOTS]
[FIREWORKS EXPLODING]
[METAL RODS CLANGING]
- [ENGINE REVVING]
- [BUS HORN HONKS]
[GLASS SHATTERING]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
- [LOUD CRASH]
[ENGINES REVVING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[GUNSHOTS]
- [TRUCK HORN HONKS
- [LOUD CRASH]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
We caught a big fish,
the gold smuggling ringleader,
Victor Zafra, alias "Tiger."
You guys got lucky.
The only reason you got me
was because of that guy
who was chasing me.
What's Zafra talking about?
Who is that guy?
I think he's also one of
Zafra's enemies.
Find out who that guy is.
That woman is at fault here.
Who is she anyway?
She has no idea
who she's messing with.
You guys know I'm the one
who finished Rudy off.
Betchay might find out.
I hired Betchay so we can use
her as leverage against Gabo
in case things get messy.
You'll bring Tiger's head
to Pops.
But you failed, so we're not
paying you anything.
You guys just
played me for a fool.
You're all full of crap.
[FIST SLAMS TABLE]
Pancit (Stir-fried noodles)
for Pops!
Pops!
Thank you.
How's Gabo's mission?
Well, Pops,
he was so sure
he'd arrest him, but... fail!
He didn't see Tiger?
Zero. Nada.
Gabo blew the whole thing, Pops!
What happened
in Chinatown?
Gabo said he almost
caught Tiger.
He was even bragging, Pops.
He said he took down
Tiger's men.
So arrogant.
Suddenly, someone fired shots,
so he had to escape.
- Who fired?
- Probably Tiger's men.
Pops, I think Gabo
is just making excuses.
[OMENG] Pops,
you need to see this.
It's on the news.
Tiger's been caught.
[DELGADO] A big fish
has been caught:
the gold smuggling ringleader,
Victor Zafra, alias "Tiger."
The exploitation of our
natural resources
and the theft from our nation
will finally stop
because of his arrest.
And I am proud to announce
tonight
that this arrest would not
be possible
if not for the NCIA agents
led by Sam Jacinto.
So Tiger's been caught.
The NCIA got him.
They're probably the ones
who shot at Gabo.
It would've been better
if we had Tiger.
Just watch. That bastard
will get out in no time.
[UWAK] With his money and
his family's influence,
they can easily buy
his freedom.
He'll just buy his way out.
And once he's out, it'll be
harder to catch him again.
Let it go. What matters is
Tiger is behind bars for now.
Tomas.
Looks like someone lost a bet.
Hey man, if you get any CCTV
footage of that guy I fought,
give it to me right away.
[REYES] Sure. I got you.
Thanks, man.
- Tuazon.
- Hm?
Why are you investigating
that guy?
Why do you think?
He messed up our mission,
obviously.
And besides that,
he kissed you, didn't he?
Can you please just drop it?
I'll handle it myself.
Why shouldn't I look into it?
I'm doing this for you,
to get back at him.
Hold on. I don't need you to
get revenge or protect me.
Did you forget?
Because of your
little fistfight,
our mission was almost blown.
So now you're taking his side?
Wow... what a flirt.
Excuse me, ma'am?
[SEBASTIAN] I'm trying to
protect you, and you're mad?
Hold on a second.
Let me remind you,
I've said it before: I don't
need your protection.
That guy is mine.
He's my problem, okay?
[BROODING MUSIC PLAYING]
What are you guys watching?
Taxpayers don't pay us to
watch our coworkers, okay?
Oh, my desk is over there.
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
[MUSIC FADES]
[UNEASY MUSIC PLAYING]
- Hand it over! Come on!
- No! Please, no!
- Please, don't.
- Stab her right now!
Please, have mercy!
I need this money
- for my husband's surgery.
- Hand it over.
- Give us the money now!
- [YELPS] Stop it!
- I'll give it to you!
- Hand it over!
- Give it up!
- [BETCHAY WHIMPERS]
Ouch! I can't give this up...
It's for my husband's surgery.
- Ma!
- Gabo!
- Gabo, help me!
- Stay out of this!
- Gabo!
- We need the money!
- I'm being robbed!
[SOBBING]
Gabo, help me!
If you don't let go of
my mother...
and return her money...
the three of you...
I'll make sure they hold your
funerals tomorrow morning.
[BLADES UNSHEATHING]
Gabo! We don't want trouble!
We're giving back your
mother's money!
- Let's go!
[BETCHAY WHIMPERS]
Ma?
[SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING]
[BLADES SHEATHING]
[PAPER RUSTLING]
Ma... Ma!
- [SOMBER MUSIC CONTINUES]
- [BETCHAY SOBS SOFTLY]
Don't touch me!
I didn't need your help at all!
I could've handled those
punks myself!
You're so annoying.
[MUSIC BECOMES EMOTIONAL]
[RALLOS CLEARS THROAT]
Ah, sir.
Looks like
Ma'am Sam keeps rejecting you.
She's just playing hard to get.
- Jacinto will be mine someday.
- I know that, sir,
because I know you have
a lot of hidden techniques.
I mean, others do
prohibited techniques, you know?
Come here, Rallos.
You know, what I like most...
...is something
that challenges me.
Something that gives me
a very hard time.
That's what I like.
And what Jacinto's doing
to me...
...is making me lose my sanity!
Don't worry.
Jacinto will be mine.
That's why you're my idol, sir.
[FISTS BUMP]
[PIA] Sam!
[PIA BREATHES]
Oh, why does it seem
like your mood's heavy
despite a successful mission?
But is it really
mission accomplished?
Is there something
you would like to ask?
There is! Um...
But I won't ask you.
I'll ask your agents.
I'll review your case
because it's too messy!
A lot of NCIA agents
were injured.
Like you just abandoned them.
It's like...
[SMACKS LIPS]
You weren't prepared.
Ma'am Pia, it's not true
that we weren't prepared.
Accidents are inevitable
in an operation.
Don't explain.
I'm just telling you
I'm going to investigate.
So you won't be surprised!
I'm nice enough, see?
I gave you a heads-up.
[PIA SCOFFS]
[UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING]
[DOOR OPENS]
- Ma'am Sam.
- How did it go?
The man we were after escaped.
- Did you see his face?
- No, ma'am. I'm sorry.
He got away?
Who could that man be?
I don't know who he is.
But I know he ruined our plan.
I'll make sure I'll find out
who he is.
Woo!
[CHUCKLING, CLAPPING]
- Woo!
- [UWAK CHCUKLING]
- How about that?
- Well?
- Give it!
- You lost the bet!
- You just got lucky.
- [UWAK CHUCKLING]
- And Gabo was just unlucky!
- [LAWIN] Hmm.
No one's lucky or unlucky.
We know Gabo!
He's a bit good.
Just a bit, okay?
But he has no strategy.
He'll be better
in the mission.
That is if there's a next one.
That is if Pops will give him
another chance.
You just got lucky.
- Give it!
- Pay up!
- [OMENG] Fine, fine.
There's no such thing as luck.
Mm-hmm!
[DOOR OPENS]
[ARTURO] Ma'am, sir.
Attorney is here.
Attorney.
Attorney, find a way
to get Victor
out of jail right now.
- I'll try, ma'am.
- What?
You'll try? Don't just try.
Do it!
We pay you so much,
so do your job!
Ma'am.
It won't be easy
to get Sir Victor out.
It's the NCIA that caught him.
They have solid evidence.
[MARIANO] Attorney.
Money can solve that.
Look for a greedy agent
in the NCIA.
Slap them with money
just to get Victor out.
[LUCAS] Well,
what are you doing?
- Go to my brother!
- [ARTURO] Attorney, let's go.
We lost 100 million pesos
because Victor's transaction
in Malaysia did not happen!
Who knows how many more
transactions we lost
because of this incident?!
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
If that lawyer fails,
I know another way
we can do this.
What?
The woman who arrested Victor...
...is General Ricardo
Jacinto's daughter.
Your former chief?
He wasn't just my boss.
We have a deep history.
And I know a lot more about him.
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
[RICARDO EXHALES]
[OBJECTS THUDDING]
[OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING]
[PHONE RINGING]
Hello? Who is this?
It's Mariano. Mariano Zafra.
You wouldn't have called
if it's not important.
What do we have to discuss?
You probably know
why I called.
[RICARDO] I heard about your son
from last night's news.
My son
whom your daughter arrested!
[MARIANO] I have no issue
with you.
We have no issues
with each other.
But this might cause a rift
between us, Ricardo.
Are you threatening me?
I don't do threats, Ricardo,
you know that.
I don't know what's going
through my daughter's head.
I don't control her.
But I'll see what I can do.
I may have kept obeying you
back then...
But that's not the case now.
A lot of things
have changed, Ricardo.
You wouldn't want to mess
with someone like me now.
[LINE DROPS]
[PHONE THUDS]
[OMINOUS MUSIC CONTINUES]
Lucas?
Mama.
Is there any news on Victor?
We're working on it.
But Lucas,
while Victor isn't here...
this is your chance to
prove to your dad that
you can take care
of our business.
You weren't given
a chance because...
your papa only trusts Victor.
But I believe,
that you can take care of it.
Now's your chance.
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
- We need to be ready.
- [TOTO] Ma'am Sam is here!
Ma'am Sam is here!
- [ISOBEL] What?!
- She's here!
[ISOBEL] We need
to congratulate her!
Wow, Sam!
- [SQUEALS]
- Wow! Sam!
[ISOBEL LAUGHS]
I am so proud of you!
- Congratulations!
- [TOTO] Congrats, Ma'am Sam!
You showed the world-- Oh!
The universe, rather,
that you're amazing!
Oh, I'm so proud of you!
- Have a seat.
- Wow!
- We have a celebration.
- Ma'am! Ma'am!
How did you catch Tiger?
I'm sure you were
like an action star!
She could handle it even
if it was a solo mission.
And she could do it all alone!
- Right, Sam?
- You're all doing too much.
But thank you.
- What is this?
- This is for you, ma'am.
Sweetie, the cake looks good.
Maybe we could slice it?
Why are you so interested
in such a small cake?
And why did you buy
the small one?
That's all our budget
could handle!
- It's embarrassing.
- You're all so sweet.
Let's slice it.
- [SQUEALS]
- Did you hear that?!
Slice the cake! Slice it now!
[PLATES CLATTERING]
Your dad knows about
your achievement.
Ah, what did he say?
I'm sure he's proud of you.
And I told him
to congratulate you.
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Do you want me to bring Gabo?
What are your plans for him?
Are you going to give him
another chance?
Find out if...
he nearly caught Victor.
I'll tell your messengers.
I wonder where Gabo is.
Something bad must
have happened there.
Don't worry, nothing bad
will happen to him.
What do you mean?
Have you seen
those people earlier?!
They have a lot of guns!
I'm blaming Gabo!
He never told us our enemies
would be big-time people!
I'm sure they're loaded.
They had loads of bodyguards
and guns!
I'm worried Gabo won't make it
back here alive.
He might be dead!
- Hey!
- Hey, don't say that!
- Stop that!
- [IPE] You shouldn't say that.
He's like a cat.
He won't die easily.
And I'm pretty sure
he won't get caught alive.
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Hey! Hey!
It's Gabo! He's alive!
Gabo!
- Gabo!
[GASPS]
[TEKLA] Gabo!
[CRYING] Gabo!
We thought something bad
happened to you!
Are you hurt? How are you?
What happened?
Did you catch Tiger?
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
I caught him.
But a bunch of people came.
They shot at me.
That's why they got him!
Whoa, Gabo!
We already know your style.
We all live in Tondo.
- Mhm-hmm.
- Maybe you just
took all the money.
We all struggled to find Tiger.
C'mon, take the money out.
He's right, Gabo.
Where is it?
Is that what you think of me?
If you think I got
the reward money,
do you think I'd be here?!
I should've gone straight
to the hospital
to pay for my fathers surgery!
You two just don't think,
do you?
Don't compare Gabo to you!
You're all annoying me!
If that's what happened...
then that's a bummer.
You caught him, but he got away!
I am sure the police will
benefit from that.
Oh, wait a minute.
I think the woman I fought
with at the jewelry store
was a police officer!
I've seen her at the bar!
She pushed us, Gabo!
That's why the man she was
with punched you!
I'll step on her like a bug
when I see her around!
We went up against big people.
And they look like
an organized syndicate.
[SIGHS]
What will we do, Gabo?
Where will we look for money
to fund Rudy's operation?
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
I don't know.
All I know is that...
I need to move so they can
start his operation.
It's best if we drink to that.
We'll find a way to help Rudy.
You're right. Hey!
One beer for Gabo!
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
Here.
Have these photocopied
first thing tomorrow.
Make 10 copies.
I'll leave early
to solicit money.
- Put it here.
- Okay.
[BETCHAY SIGHS SHARPLY]
[MAMENG] Hey.
Where were you?
I hustled to make money,
what else?
Hmm?
Well, did you make money?
A bit.
Just chump change.
You got that illegally, huh?
See? It's annoying, isn't it?
Whatever!
There's my contribution!
Don't tell me
I didn't contribute!
Uh, wait, Betchay.
Speaking of contributions,
can I...
Can I have some of it
to make copies of these?
Take it.
- Really?
- Yeah.
[MAMENG] Take care of that.
That's a huge amount.
- [DANTE] Of course. I will.
- Seriously?!
You don't know what I
went through for that.
How could you belittle me?
I didn't! I just said
it was a huge amount!
I can't believe this!
I said it was a huge amount
- so he should take care of it!
- I should go.
You talk as if you're all that.
- [TOTO] Here I go! Here I go!
- Okay!
H-Here-- Here comes Sir Ricardo.
- Oh!
- He's here.
Case closed, Sam?
Ah, yes, Dad.
We caught the suspect.
But we still need
to strengthen the case.
Sam, you don't know
the person you're up against.
He's a powerful man.
Are you sure
about your investigation?
We only had a limited time
to study the case,
but when we got the chance
to arrest the suspect,
we didn't hesitate.
Maybe you were mistaken
about Victor Zafra.
I mean, he could've just
been caught in the crossfire
between you and
the real suspect.
Dad, he exchanged fire
with the NCIA.
And he's been doing
illegal transactions.
Sam.
The Zafras are operating
legitimate businesses.
What illegal transactions
are you talking about?
Do you have evidence?
Did you find contraband on him?
No, they managed
to take it away.
Then maybe you caught
the wrong guy!
[SAM] That's impossible, Dad!
He has an existing murder case!
And he's the leader
of the gold-smuggling syndicate!
Hang on.
Are you defending him?
I'm not defending Victor Zafra!
I'm just asking what you
and your agency did!
Wait, Dad.
We studied this case properly
and followed due process.
The NCIA was able to arrest
a criminal because of me.
I believe I did my job
the best way I know how.
Are you really
questioning me on this?
Is that wrong in your eyes too?
Sam!
[MOROSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Stop it.
You better listen to Dad.
Stop insisting you're right.
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
Max, you better
talk to your sister.
You never fail to impress me.
Not only did you forget
to congratulate your daughter,
you even questioned her
for arresting a criminal.
Is it wrong of me
to give her the right advice?
Advice? You made it seem
like she's done nothing right!
Like everything she does
is wrong!
Isobel.
This is the real world.
That's not how an honorable
law enforcer should act!
There it is.
It all comes down
to the same thing with you.
You always talk about honor and
how you were a great general.
How the police force
looked up to you.
Ricardo, for once, forget
that you're a former general.
Just be a father!
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR THUDS]
What was that about?
Why are you asking me?
Ask Dad.
He thinks I'm wrong again.
Am I wrong for doing
my job right?
You talked back at him.
Do you think that's right?
Don't do that again,
especially when I'm here.
Am I wrong for
defending myself?
It's not like
I disrespected Dad.
I was just telling him
the truth.
Dad sees something
that we don't, Sam.
We're just new cops.
He's a former chief of police.
He knows a lot about cases
and criminals.
Please learn to listen
to him.
Am I wrong for defending
myself?
That's what I'm asking.
Am I wrong for
solving the case?
Fine. You want to know
what's wrong?
Let's start with that agency
of yours.
Your team should've
coordinated with us.
We're the ones handling Zafra's
case, but you took it from us.
Why are you blaming
my team?
It's not our fault that NLEA
is slow at solving cases.
My team and I caught
a big-time criminal.
Yeah, right!
You're so good at your job!
You never listen, Sam!
In case you forgot,
our family got ruined because
of your stubbornness!
[MOROSE MUSIC PLAYING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[DOOR OPENS, CLOSES]
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
The police fear me and they
follow all my orders.
My word is the law.
I can't let this pass,
even if it means going
against my daughter.
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
It's payback time!
Find the guy who
attacked our group.
It's his fault that I'm here
in jail.
And it must be paid
with life.
Bring him to me. He has to
pay for what he did to Victor.
Will you give up
your principles...
Are you going to let
your father die
and not get surgery?
I almost sold my soul
for him.
...for something you need?
We need money!
That's what we need!
I'm here to offer assistance
for Mister Rudy.
Which will Gabo choose?
You can't put an amount
on my father!
We'll make sure the person
who did that to my father
will go to jail!
Sir, what about my
possible suspension?
The board will decide on
whatever you deserve.
Our mission would've gone
smooth if not for that guy.
Who is he anyway?
Was he the guy who kissed you?
I'm only sure about one thing.
I want to meet that guy
so I can arrest him.